how do you define true Ed and how do you
determine what ruit to treat it is there
an order of approaches you go through
that's a tricky one you know and like if
I was given if I was still in urology
I'd probably give you some academic e
type answer um but even then knowing
knowing in neurology what we actually do
dayto day on the real side of things
it's still a lot of just well let's try
this if that doesn't work let's try this
and if that doesn't work let's try this
it's always a stepwise progression now
if something in somebody's
history indicates there might be a
structural problem an anatomic problem I
mean obviously if they've a young guy
that's been in a car wreck and has had a
pelvic fracture something you know
that's kind of obvious um but for these
kind of random where it's like doesn't
make sense that they're having Ed
because they're healthy
otherwise um I would still not try to go
straight for like invasive procedures
like penal Doppler even is not invasive
but it's embarrassing uh and it and it
doesn't always going to give it's not
going to always tell you what we should
do it's still going to be like well we
need to improve blood flow so here's
some sealas right um now if they have
Venus leak or something like that that
might be useful to know uh but I would I
wouldn't jump to that first that's going
to be more a process of
elimination um but if you if you go look
at the textbook chapters on Ed my gosh
they're they're painful and long um a
lot of guys it's obviously psychogenic
you know you know or at least there's a
component of that you have to look at
everything in their life you have to
look at their stress levels their diet
their medication list is a huge one a
lot of these guys even young guys
nowadays are on a freaking blood
pressure pill and a Statin so okay
recipe for Ed right there um and they
don't think twice about it and I'm like
30y old I'm like why are you on a
stattin and two blood pressure well my
doctor told me I needed it it's like
just kills me you know so you know we
are being poisoned left and right not
just by the food and everything else but
doctors are poisoning people without and
again I don't bmer people for taking a
pill if they feel like they need it to
mitigate some symptom they're having
that they're worried about but they need
to have informed consent about that they
need to know and the doctors have to
tell them hey I'm GNA put you on this
blood pressure pill but here's what can
happen you may start having Ed you may
start having swelling in your ankle I
mean all this list
and they just don't usually do that and
that's my beef with most providers in
general whether it's surgical side or
medical not most but a lot um just be
upfront with people be honest with
people about everything you know within
reason that's possible so that people
aren't freaking out you know that's the
that's the thing just know what you're
getting into so